Contact

henrik.kniberg@crisp.se

www.linkedin.com/in/hkniberg (LinkedIn) blog.crisp.se/henrikkniberg (Blog) www.crisp.se/henrik.kniberg (Company)

Top Skills

Teaching
Artificial Intelligence (AI)
Coaching & Mentoring

Certifications

Certified Scrum Trainer
Certified LeSS practitioner
Advanced Certified Scrum Developer
Certified Scrum Professional®Developer
CSD® Educator

Publications

Version Control for Multiple Agile Teams

How Spotify Builds Products Spotify Engineering Culture Kanban and Scrum - Making the Most of Both

Lean from the Trenches: Managing Large-Scale Projects with Kanban

Henrik Kniberg

Al whisperer. Chief Scientist & Cofounder of Hups.com. Cofounder of GoClimate.com. Teemyco advisor. Crisp consultant. Previously Spotify coach, LEGO coach, Minecraft dev @ Mojang. Like to jam! Greater Stockholm Metropolitan Area

Summary

Currently focused on applied AI - how to use generative AI (GPT etc) to improve productivity and build awesome products/services.

I've done Minecraft design/development at Mojang, also coach the teams using Agile & Lean principles and methods like Scrum, XP, and Kanban. Previously worked with Spotify and LEGO, helping to implement agile culture there and in other fast-moving and fast-growing environments.

I cofounded Hups.com together with Niklas Modig. We create selfimproving organizations!

I accidentally sort of co-created something called the Spotify Model. https://labs.spotify.com/2014/03/27/spotify-engineering-culture-part-1

I'm into climate change, and co-founded http://GoClimate.com. Help us save the world!

For more info see http://www.crisp.se/henrik.kniberg, or my blog http://blog.crisp.se/author/henrikkniberg

Experience

Hups
Chief Scientist & Co-Founder
January 2021 - Present (2 years 9 months)
Stockholm

Teemyco Advisor February 2023 - Present (8 months) Greens Ventures
Founding Investor
August 2022 - Present (1 year 2 months)

Crisp

Co-owner & AI whisperer September 2005 - Present (18 years 1 month) www.crisp.se

Mojang AB

Minecraft designer/developer/coach February 2018 - May 2022 (4 years 4 months) Stockholm

Minecraft gameplay design, development, and team coaching.

GoClimate

Co-Founder
September 2017 - January 2022 (4 years 5 months)
http://www.goclimate.com
A way for everyone to help stop combat change.

LEGO Group

Agile/Lean coach December 2014 - November 2016 (2 years) Billund, Denmark

Agile/Lean coaching. Helped with implementing and scaling an agile organization of about 20 teams. Mentored leaders and teams and spread seeds of agile thinking in various parts of the organization. Did internal training, facilitation, workshops, and individual coaching. Some of the experiences documented in this article "Scaling Agile at LEGO":

https://blog.crisp.se/2016/12/30/henrikkniberg/agile-lego

Spotify

Agile/Lean coach May 2012 - November 2016 (4 years 7 months) Stockholm

Coached and mentored managers and teams, helped introduce and spread Agile & Lean mindset and practices across the organization. Watched the org grow from a few hundred to several thousand in the space of 5 years.

Documented the experiences in several viral articles and videos about Spotify engineering culture.

Agile Alliance
Board of Directors
August 2009 - August 2011 (2 years 1 month)

Netbreeze CEO & cofounder

1997 - 2008 (11 years)

Independent software consulting. Projects include J2EE development, requirements analysis, & Development architecture. Strong focus on test-driven development and agile software. Several projects have been partially outsourced to offshore software houses in Poland and India.

Tain

Chief of development

December 2005 - April 2007 (1 year 5 months)

Lead the development team (approximately 40 developers), promoted good design practices, and established effective routines for requirements, development, quality assurance, release management, etc. Hired as consultant, not employed.

Used Scrum and XP (agile software development methods), TDD (test-driven development), Java/J2EE, and a host of well-established technologies including Spring framework, Hibernate, Tapestry, JBoss, Oracle DB, MySQL DB, etc.

Epicent

CTO & cofounder

January 2003 - December 2005 (3 years)

Mobile services. Patented technology for connecting mobile phones with PCs regardless of distance.

Ace Interactive

System design team lead

March 2004 - December 2004 (10 months)

As consultant I led the system design team for a client/server gaming terminal system, and introduced agile practices such as TDD (test-driven development).

Goyada CTO & cofounder 1998 - 2002 (4 years)

Recruited & led the technical team (20 people at peak). Designed and developed most of the technical platform and architecture. Extensive usage of technologies and tools such as J2EE, EJB, XML, JSP, HTTP, Struts, JUnit, Ant, OODB, and RDB. Developed several patents related to mobile services. Set up partnerships with hosting companies, consulting companies, and offshore developers.

Education

KTH Royal Institute of Technology

Master's Degree, Computer Science · (1993 - 2014)